<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Deep Roots]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/</link><image><url>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/lib/media/favicon.svg</url><title>Deep Roots</title><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/</link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 02:15:51 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/lib/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 02:15:48 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator/><item><title><![CDATA[Professor Ssimmia Hakani]]></title><description><![CDATA[<a class="tag" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/?query=tag:Creature" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#Creature</a> <a class="tag" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/?query=tag:NPC" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#NPC</a> <a class="tag" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/?query=tag:DigTeam" style="background-color: rgb(4, 108, 116); color: white; font-weight: 700; border: none; border-radius: 1em; padding: 0.2em 0.5em;">#DigTeam</a> <br> Infobox <img alt="zephyrqu_afropunk_she_has_scaled_skin_blue_robe_72461c9f-ac90-4e4a-9e96-c926a9792db5.png" src="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/zephyrqu_afropunk_she_has_scaled_skin_blue_robe_72461c9f-ac90-4e4a-9e96-c926a9792db5.png" target="_self"> <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Aurora Sanctum" data-href="Aurora Sanctum" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Aurora Sanctum" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aurora Sanctum</a>
<br>Prof Ssimmia Hakani, one of the curators at the Aurora Sanctum (a museum in northeastern <a data-href="Baheera" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/prime-material-plane,-rakāuvi/baheera/baheera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Baheera</a>) who is a colleague of <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Thaddeus Quill" data-href="Thaddeus Quill" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Thaddeus Quill" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Thaddeus</a> and invited him and his companions down into the dig to meet the other researchers.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Locations/Prime Material Plane, Rakāuvi/Baheera/Arkehost Oasis/Arkehost Oasis.md" data-href="Locations/Prime Material Plane, Rakāuvi/Baheera/Arkehost Oasis/Arkehost Oasis.md" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/prime-material-plane,-rakāuvi/baheera/arkehost-oasis/arkehost-oasis.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Arkehost Oasis</a><br>]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/dig-team/professor-ssimmia-hakani.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Entities/NPCs/Dig Team/Professor Ssimmia Hakani.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 02:12:08 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/zephyrqu_afropunk_she_has_scaled_skin_blue_robe_72461c9f-ac90-4e4a-9e96-c926a9792db5.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/zephyrqu_afropunk_she_has_scaled_skin_blue_robe_72461c9f-ac90-4e4a-9e96-c926a9792db5.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aerendyl 44]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Day 4 of Firecrest, T.A. 515? | Day 13 in the Feywild<br>
I had time on my hands before the first few of us would go to bed, so I finished my conversation with <a data-href="Toraash" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Toraash" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toraash</a>. Their insights on the <a data-href="Spellplague" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/spellplague.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spellplague</a> and the evolution of magic have given me much to ponder and research in the future, both at their request and for the sake of my own rekindled curiosity.<br>It also turned out that <a data-href="Oona" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Oona" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Oona</a>, a fallen companion of <a data-href="Faen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/faen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Faen</a>'s and an old friend of Toraash’, is … here, sort of? I still don't fully understand. The shape of this shrine is equal to Oona's form when they were still around, but these are not their remains, I was told. Either way, I made sure to say goodbye on Toraash’ behalf before we left.<br>After that, I worked on a ring for myself; something to help replace the forefinger I lost in <a data-href="Baheera" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/prime-material-plane,-rakāuvi/baheera/baheera.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Baheera</a>, albeit with a little extra functionality. <a data-href="Deidre" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/deidre.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Deidre</a>'s help was incredibly useful. The job isn't done yet, but we're well on our way. I've also made sure we have plenty of powdered silver and iron, and while rummaging through my pack, I also discovered I had more holy water that I just forgot about. It's all about the little things, right?<br>I also asked <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Meilikki" data-href="Meilikki" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/meilikki.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mielikki</a> for some water from her pond. I imagined I'd need it to clean myself off after what I had planned for <a data-href="Grout" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/grout.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Grout</a> (read on if you wish to learn, whoever you might be …). That, and refilling my waterskin, of course. For all the caution we've had to employ in terms of giving back when we take something, a small seed from the dreamgrass flower she appreciated last time only seemed fitting. [ Imagine a messy sketch of a weed leaf here ]<br>When it was time to take first watch, I settled in with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Luck of the Draw" data-href="Luck of the Draw" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/luck-of-the-draw.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Luck</a>. I think this is only the second time since he joined our little band of misfits that I've had a moment alone with him, actually. I'm happy I got around to having a conversation with him in private, as it led to me trusting him with the acorn of resurrection. Of course I would have rather held on to it myself, but I know that is only the difficulty of relinquishing control speaking. At least it's not greed; I'll take comfort in that.<br>I simply figured with his focus homing in on his allegiance to <a data-href="the Raven Queen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/the-raven-queen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Raven Queen</a> and her tenets, he will be the least likely to abuse it – whether intentionally or not –, along with myself. Although our reasons for it may be different, with myself seeking to maintain the delicate balance between life and death, and him … not necessarily, I suppose, the point stands. Besides, who knows where I might wind up once we encounter <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Vestan Tlanbourn" data-href="Vestan Tlanbourn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Vestan Tlanbourn" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Vestan</a>. I wouldn't put it past myself to end up somewhere well out of reach of someone who needs what the acorn can provide if or when the time for that comes. <br>My attempt to reach <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Da'yin Kuya of Infinite Facets" data-href="Da'yin Kuya of Infinite Facets" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/da'yin-kuya-of-infinite-facets.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Da'yin</a> once I got to sleep was frustratingly brief, but her assurance of my mother's safety in the <a data-href="Tower of Ionna" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Tower of Ionna" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Tower of Ionna</a> brought some relief. Her plea for my return weighs heavily on my heart, though, especially given the dangers we face — and the voracious hole left in place of what could've only been the urge to cry at receiving this news about her. It's so much easier to cope with when it simply doesn't cross your mind …<br>A few hours later, the began with unexpected gifts and preparations. <a data-href="Corvaux" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/corvaux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Corvaux</a> gifted me a lump of adamantine and some bloodseeker arrows — a welcome surprise! I wonder if them finding it here (at least, I presume they found it here) has anything to do with Oona perhaps having touched down here during their fall? It is, after all, an ore found in meteor craters.<br>But there was more to this morning, of course: I bound Grout to me as my familiar! Granted, it almost went sideways and I think it would've taken only one more loss of focus for us both to tumble into one of those pools around us, but it panned out in the end. Little man’s got a beautiful pair of wings on him now, and eyes so luminescent, I fully expect them to frighten me in the dark on at least one occasion.<br>Before we set out, Deidre, <a data-href="Mirri" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/mirri.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mirri</a> and <a data-href="Merisande" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Merisande" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Merisande</a> went back up to try one last time to get rid of the bloodied handprints, but that – apparently – didn't go according to plan. I'm not entirely sure what happened, but, in any case, we'll need to address the matter by ‘addressing’ Vestan, I suppose.<br>We then finally ventured deeper into the <a data-href="Underfey" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Underfey" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Underfey</a>, where we all too sound came upon a fork in the road. Both paths revealed the presence of Vestan's cultists nearby. Our group has split to handle the threat — Corvaux, Luck, Merisande and I heading right to confront the lone orc, while Mirri, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Smoke-in-Mirrors" data-href="Smoke-in-Mirrors" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Smoke-in-Mirrors" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Smoke</a> and Deidre attempt to gather information from the group on the left. ]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/aerendyl-44.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Aerendyl 44.md</guid><pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 02:10:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mirri 43]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Flamecrest, 515 of 3A.<br>I can’t think straight. My head is still spinning from the lochathi’s grasping claws. <a data-href="Hallow" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/hallow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hallow</a> is not answering me. Don’t do this to me, not now. Not when we are so close to the end.<br>Focus, Mirri. Pay attention. Eclipse. When is the next eclipse? <a data-href="Wisp" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/crimson-gaze/wisp.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Wisp</a> says 100 days. Could he be fabricating one? Is that what the little goblin was talking about, gathering materials? Are there material components that must be consumed in great quantities for it to happen?<br>And what of me? What parts of me must be consumed to assist in his ascent? My soul? My very being?<br>
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Aerendyl" data-href="Aerendyl" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/aerendyl.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aeren</a> has decided to speak with <a data-href="Toraash" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Toraash" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toraash</a>, to search the heavens for some answer. My head hurts. What… what about the book? The first? The one that led me here? What did it say? Is there an answer there? Those notes are… decades old. Written on the second page of my Book of Shadows.<br>Someone is coming down the path.<br>Her name is <a data-href="Merisande" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Merisande" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Merisande</a> of <a data-href="the Hollow Tower" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/the Hollow Tower" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Hollow Tower</a>. I’ve heard of it before, considered searching for it myself, once. She’s after—<br>He called himself Tyvan then. He tended<br>
She took him to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Court of Aetheria" data-href="Court of Aetheria" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/prime-material-plane,-rakāuvi/sylvari/court-of-aetheria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aetheria</a> and they<br>they <br>He wed? Her? He bowed his head before the gods and swore himself for eternity to <br>How. how fucking DARE YOU<br>he<br>he did it again. he did it again he did it again he did it again he diditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagainhediditagain again aGAIN *AGAIN AGAIN AGAIN*<br><a data-href="Kamina" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Kamina" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Kamina</a>. Her name is Kamina.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/mirri-43.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Mirri 43.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 23:25:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aerendyl 43]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>[ * Spoiler-tagged parts are speculations re: Vestan and who he is to Mirri lmao ]<br>
Day 3 of Firecrest, T.A. 515? | Day 12 in the Feywild<br>
<a data-href="Toraash" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Toraash" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toraash</a>’s disgruntlement at the revelation surrounding the mural overhead drew me back towards them; into the staff, I suppose. Our talk revealed alarming possibilities about the eclipse <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Vestan Tlanbourn" data-href="Vestan Tlanbourn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Vestan Tlanbourn" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Vestan</a> may be planning. The Sun-Eating Dragon, or ‘Dreameater’ as I’ve heard it being called, poses a significant threat if we interfere with any celestial events. Toraash's warning about Vestan potentially fabricating an eclipse doesn’t put me at ease, either, especially when <a data-href="Wisp" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/crimson-gaze/wisp.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Wisp</a> confirmed the next natural eclipse is at least 100 days away.<br>However, I suppose the dragon’s revenge will be swift if Vestan interferes, himself. As I write this, I have to wonder if letting Vestan proceed would result in the dragon dealing with him for us. Though, even if it came to that, I imagine we’ll get wiped out right along with him.<br>I can recall three methods of creating artificial eclipses:<br>
<br>The Eternal Eclipse of Xul'rath requires consuming four primordial gems, sacrificing a celestial dragon, and reciting a years-long hymn.
<br>The Incantation of the Midnight Sun — a volatile spell summoning an earth and flame elemental to consume the sun.
<br>The Devouring, a ritual where the caster sacrifices their heart, eyes, and tongue to the Void for the power to cast the world into night.
<br>Toraash also mentioned <a data-href="Mordiggian's Maw" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Mordiggian's Maw" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mordiggian's Maw</a>, a constellation believed to predict eclipses that drives observers mad over time.<br>Our discussion was interrupted by the arrival of <a data-href="Merisande" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Merisande" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Merisande</a> of <a data-href="the Hollow Tower" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/the Hollow Tower" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Hollow Tower</a>, a celestial (I believe?) seeking our help to stop Vestan. Her story shook us to our core. She had been married to Vestan, known to her as Tyvan, and bore him a child named <a data-href="Kamina" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Kamina" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Kamina</a> before he took off. This hit <a data-href="Mirri" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/mirri.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mirri</a> hard; I watched a storm of emotions cross her face — confusion, disbelief, raw envy – or jealousy? – and unbounded grief to cap it off.<br> I know the thought has crossed my mind before,<br>Spoiler
that Vestan is Mirri’s father, <br>and in particular the envy reinforces that theory. Granted, it’s not something that came into existence in a vacuum. It’s her discomfort with the disguises of him she’s worn recently, the joke about his liking for redheads — truly, <br>Spoiler
I’d be surprised if her mother didn’t have a shock of red hair, now.
<br>Merisande's account of Vestan’s return after two decades, cold and changed, aligns disturbingly with what we know of Vestan. The possibility that Kamina, <br>Spoiler
potentially Mirri's half-sibling, <br>might have been Vestan's latest victim, instills as much sorrow in me as it does ire. I cannot imagine the heartbreak it took for Merisande to reach us …<br>
Speaking of her: she referred to us by some cryptic titles: I am "The Gate," Mirri "The Sword," Deidre "The Jewel," and Luck "The Knight", if i recall correctly. Curiously, she couldn't "see" Corvaux at all. I’m not sure if she meant ‘see’ in her prophetic dreams, or ‘see’ past their physical form here, in the physical world. I wonder if these designations are more of a product of our lives until now, or if they’re meant to be prophetic.<br>In any case: we've agreed to include Merisande in our plans. We don’t know how exactly, but we’ll come to that before we depart, I presume. However, Mirri's private conversation with her leaves me uneasy. I caught glimpses of Merisande's anxiety and eagerness, but Mirri's reaction remains a mystery. The closer we get to the culmination of this quest of ours, the more I begin to wonder when the other shoe will drop. What is she not ready to tell us? And why do I feel it is so bloody pertinent to our cause?<br>I’m not the type to forcefully draw it out of her, but gods know I’ve tried to gently coax. It – as usual – left me with more questions than answers.<br>For now, I prepare for our rest. I suspect this will be the last time and place we can feel even marginally safe. And in that safety, under the <a data-href="Serenity of the Sisters" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Serenity of the Sisters" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Serenity of the Sisters</a>’ eyes, I believe I should prepare not only myself for the journey ahead, but <a data-href="Grout" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/grout.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Grout</a>, too. ]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/aerendyl-43.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Aerendyl 43.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 23:19:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mirri 42]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Flamecrest, 515 of 3A.<br>
Day 13 in <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Feywild" data-href="Feywild" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Feywilds</a><br>The little balls of light were Will-o-wisps; they were fast and nearly impossible to hit. But we managed in the end. <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Luck of the Draw" data-href="Luck of the Draw" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/luck-of-the-draw.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Luck</a> and <a data-href="Corvaux" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/corvaux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Corvaux</a> took watch on each end of this crystal cavern. While we rested and those who were wounded recuperated… I wandered back into the main cavern.<br>The water was murky, but still enough for me to catch a glimpse of my reflection. The swirling aurora was still there in my eyes and I was starting to wonder if the effect was permanent. The thought of it left me… conflicted. I focused on the pattern, on my appearance as a whole. I have magic now that can change it, far easier than any costume or cosmetic I’ve used before, and when I opened my eyes again, they were back to normal. Dark hazel brown. So I do have some control over it!<br>What I did next was purely selfish. Self-indulgent. Something I had never dared attempt before… I changed my eyes again. As soft and green as the fields of Orllanar. To see my face staring back at me with their eyes… It was surreal. It brought up a thousand “what-ifs”, things I had wondered all my life. Would it have been easier if I looked like this instead of…<br>Back to brown. The green doesn’t suit me. I wish it did.<br>We decided that our time here would be longer than originally expected. There was the muddy cavern we had only barely investigated and so that was where I headed first while <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Aerendyl" data-href="Aerendyl" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/aerendyl.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aeren</a> and Luck returned to fetch <a data-href="Grout" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/grout.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Grout</a> and <a data-href="Ralph" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/ralph.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ralph</a>. There was a massive curtain of ivy and small green motes dancing in the air. It brought to mind the shrine to <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Meilikki" data-href="Meilikki" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/meilikki.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mielikki</a> in the house above. Leaving <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Rorschach Hastaerien Blackwell Ni'Tessine, III, Esq." data-href="Rorschach Hastaerien Blackwell Ni'Tessine, III, Esq." href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/rorschach-hastaerien-blackwell-ni'tessine,-iii,-esq..html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Rorschach</a> behind, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Smoke-in-Mirrors" data-href="Smoke-in-Mirrors" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Smoke-in-Mirrors" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Smoke</a>, <a data-href="Deidre" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/deidre.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Deidre</a>, and I slipped quietly into the tunnel, following it until it opened into another cavern… a shrine of some kind? Smoke excitedly said that this must be a temple to Mielikki and her sisters. But my greatest surprise was that there was a shrine to <a data-href="the Librarian" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/the Librarian" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Librarian</a> here.<br>The moment Smoke and Deidre stepped away, I tried to invoke her. Do you pray to an Archfey like you do the gods? I haven’t done that since I was a small girl, but I had to try. I asked for help defeating him. And, if I must be specific… I asked about the <a data-href="Eldoumiir" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Eldoumiir" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Eldoumiir</a> Line. It has been on my mind since before we arrived here in the Feywild—the <a data-href="Archive" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Archive" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Archive</a> said he was a descendant of that line. The root of all of this—literally &amp; figuratively— may lie with them. Who were they? What happened to them? Are they still around? Will I find <a data-href="Xyrra" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Xyrra" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Xyrra</a>’s name among them or was she a lie, too?<br>It wasn’t until Aeren returned with Luck that we understood exactly where we were; this is the <a data-href="Serenity of the Sisters" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Serenity of the Sisters" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Serenity of the Sisters</a>!<br>What joy I felt at knowing this was soon snatched away as Aeren began to translate the <a data-href="Druidic" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/languages/druidic.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Druidic</a> text on the ceiling mural. The <a data-href="Sun Devourer" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Sun Devourer" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Sun Devourer</a>. The eclipse, the doorway, the <a data-href="Abyss" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/abyss/abyss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Abyss</a>, the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shadowfel" data-href="Shadowfel" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/shadowfel/shadowfel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shadowfell</a>. Fuck. Fuck! So this is how he means to do it? His ascent delivered on a silver spoon with this doorway?<br>And yet… it might also be a chance I have to take. What if that opening is my chance to free <a data-href="Hallow" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/hallow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hallow</a>? The very thought of it is madness, that I might walk in his footsteps in any way, but it’s something to keep in mind. Maybe the Librarian can help me with that, too. I don’t know, nor do I have enough faith in the archfey to risk it. What I do know is that I at least owe it to Hallow to tell her what we’ve learned as soon as possible. The others are exploring the temple. Aeren and Deidre are talking—didn’t they pray at the shrine in the manor? Maybe they’re trying again. Corvaux’s gone to peer into that deep crevice at the final pool. I’ve decided to sit by the Librarian’s shrine and try to reach Hallow. This kind of information cannot wait. <br>The Lochathi was waiting. It was stupid and reckless and I should not have done it. Stop it. Stop it, let me go. Let me—<br>
<a data-href="Paelias" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Paelias" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Paelias</a>, you’re bleeding. I’m here, it’s alright. Paelias, get up. You have to get up. We’re almost home, see? See? We’re almost there. We’re going home. It’s just a bit further and we’ll be home. I have to get you home. I promised. I tried, Mama…. I’m sorry. I’m sorry. I tried. But I couldn’t… It wasn’t— I’m bleeding. My blood and his on my hands get it off get it off get it off— Cal, I’ll wait for you at the pier. I waited and waited and waited and you never came—<br>I am the harbinger of my own fate. I will not chew my nails.<br>
I will not ache for this. I am the harbinger of my own fate. I will not chew my nails. I will not ache for this. I am the harbinger of my own fate. I will not chew my nails. I will not ache for this.<br>
I am the harbinger of my own fate.<br>
I am the harbinger of my own fate.<br>
I am the harbinger of my own fate.<br>Aeren is trying to be kind. But I can’t say it. I can’t, I can’t, I can’t. I can’t say it because it will happen again. The glint of a dagger in the dark. The quiet sound of steel sinking into flesh. Blood on the kitchen floor. Stitching my own wounds closed. Leaving a scar that everyone can see.<br>Disowned, abandoned, ignored, forgotten.<br>
Alone. I don’t want to be alone.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/mirri-42.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Mirri 42.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 22:47:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aerendyl 42]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Day 3 of Firecrest, T.A. 515? | Day 12 in the <a data-href="Feywild" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Feywild</a><br>
The aftermath of our battle with the Will-o'-Wisps left us battered, but victorious. We briefly rested to recover and regroup, setting the stage for further exploration of these subterranean chambers. With that and <a data-href="Alixandria" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/alixandria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Alixandria</a>'s parting words, I suppose we're already on the <a data-href="Underfey" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Underfey" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Underfey</a>'s doorstep.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Luck of the Draw" data-href="Luck of the Draw" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/luck-of-the-draw.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Luck</a> and I made our way up, and I'm glad to learn I have not lost my magic touch entirely. Had the contrary been true, Luck might have wound up flattened by a misplaced boulder, rather than able to breeze right past it. Above ground, our discovery of <a data-href="Grout" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/grout.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Grout</a> and <a data-href="Ralph" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/ralph.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ralph</a> playing hide-and-seek brought a moment of lighthearted relief amidst the tension. Their carefree interaction was a poignant reminder of the simple joys I nowadays often overlook …<br>Upon our return below ground ( with our furry companions, Luck included ), we wound up in a chamber that appears to be a shrine to the <a data-href="Serenity of the Sisters" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Serenity of the Sisters" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Serenity of the Sisters</a> — precisely whom <a data-href="Wisp" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/crimson-gaze/wisp.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Wisp</a> had advised us to seek!<br>The altars, or rather pools, dedicated to various goddesses and powerful entities like <a data-href="Faen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/faen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Faen</a>, <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Meilikki" data-href="Meilikki" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/meilikki.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mielikki</a>, <a data-href="the Librarian" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/the Librarian" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Librarian</a>, <a data-href="Carroway" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Carroway" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Carroway</a>, <a data-href="Amara" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Amara" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Amara</a>, and <a data-href="Dahma" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Dahma" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Dahma</a>, offer a wealth of potential aid and knowledge. The inclusion of the Librarian, a rebel archfey whose primary concern – as far as I know – is to spread knowledge, among their number is particularly intriguing and potentially useful in our struggle, or various struggles.<br>The mural on the ceiling, depicting "the beast who devours the sun," meanwhile revealed crucial information about the nature of eclipses in the Feywild. The sun here isn't merely a source of light, but a portal to other realms, shifting dangerously during an eclipse. In its usual state, it should lead to the <a data-href="Fire Plane" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Fire Plane" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Fire Plane</a>. Fitting enough, but the revelation about the sun being a rift between worlds didn't stop there: it leads into the <a data-href="Abyss" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/abyss/abyss.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Abyss</a> as it shifts towards a total eclipse, before opening a way into the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shadowfel" data-href="Shadowfel" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/shadowfel/shadowfel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shadowfell</a> for the briefest of moments once total darkness is attained, only for the pattern to then be reversed again.<br>As nightmarish a finding as this is given the circumstances, this could very well be the key to understanding <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Vestan Tlanbourn" data-href="Vestan Tlanbourn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Vestan Tlanbourn" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Vestan</a>'s ultimate goal. The warning –&nbsp;or challenge –&nbsp;about the risks and potential rewards of being out during an eclipse cements the conviction that he seeks to manipulate the next upcoming eclipse. Now that spiel about ‘blotting out the sun’ makes even more sense …<br>Either way, I now await word from Wisp. I hope she knows when the next eclipse here will occur. As a druid of the Circle of Stars, she of all people might have an idea about this, I suppose.<br><a data-href="Deidre" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/deidre.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Deidre</a> meanwhile put up quite the show, enticing lustermites to dance to her tune and uncovering a slew of additional names belonging to the Serenity of the Sisters – before she decides to drink from Mielikki's pool. Now, I am not wont to mistrust deities per se, but this to me seemed an unnecessarily brazen move. However, the Feywild and the powers that be there have a way of proving me wrong at every turn: the mouthful of water yielded a mysterious diamond.<br>All in all: a strange blend of dire discovery and light-hearted communication, at least until <a data-href="Mirri" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/mirri.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mirri</a>'s communion with <a data-href="Hallow" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/hallow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hallow</a> went awry. A gut-wrenching scream heralded her return to the here and now before storming out of the shrine.<br>( Was Hallow perhaps no longer there, or wounded, or no longer herself, even? Did the locathi get to either of them? )<br>
I had to chase after her. How could I not, even against the odds that she might not even want to see me or anyone else as she confronted … whatever pains that happening stirred to life?<br>Her anguish, the blood, the scrubbing and the cryptic mantra about being "the harbinger of her own fate" hint at a burden far heavier than I had imagined.<br>She kept staring at her reflection in the water. Her refusal to truly tell me who she expected to see there – or perhaps was afraid to see – was expected, but hard to swallow all the same. She referenced the scar on her cheek from a previous encounter in which she chose honesty regarding what she deemed plain to see as a reason not to do so. It hurts to think she might believe her present company could do such a thing to her, but then … how can I blame or even judge her? We don't all deal with pain by sharing it.<br>She also referred the promise she made to get me home — a risky thing I believe, now we know what we know about promise magic. This, I don't fully understand. How does that impact her ability to be truthful? The depth of her trauma and the secrets she carries are obviously taking a toll, and I worry about the impact this will have on our her, our objective and our group as a whole.<br>Ah … shit, I don't know. If there's anything I've learned, it's that I know very little, and can infer even less.<br>For now, we have more work to do. The information about the eclipse and its potential role in Vestan's plans adds to our urgency, so we must swiftly decipher these clues, harness any power and wisdom offered by the Serenity of the Sisters, and find a way to stop Vestan before he can manipulate these cosmic forces for his sinister purposes.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/aerendyl-42.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Aerendyl 42.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 18:34:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mirri 41]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Flamecrest, 515 of 3A.<br>
Day 13 in the Feywilds<br>Looking again at these bloody handprints. <a data-href="Aerendyl" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/aerendyl.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aerendyl</a> suggested consulting <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Malachai" data-href="Malachai" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Malachai" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Stonecutter</a>’s journal, hoping that there may be an answer there. <a data-href="Corvaux" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/corvaux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Corvaux</a> and I agreed to help and what we found was impressive. The journal chronicles Malachai’s attempts to find out where souls were disappearing. He’s faced obyrith, fae, demons, etc., as well as experimented and attempted to create new spells that might assist his journey. There were details about elvish souls that should have reincarnated, mortals who vanished into the <a data-href="Feywild" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Feywild</a> under strange circumstances… He performed “errands” for <a data-href="the Raven Queen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/the-raven-queen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Raven Queen</a> and searched the River Styx. And yet all he could find was that dark shadows have shrouded some black hole that has presumably been “consuming” these souls… thousands upon thousands of them.<br>That kind of power could be used, Malachai surmises, to brute-force an ascension to divinity. Because of fucking course that’s what it means.<br>As horrific as it sounds, as guilty as the thought makes me… I am almost glad, now, that <a data-href="Paelias" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Paelias" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Paelias</a> is trapped here, with me. It means his soul is safe, for the time being. Perhaps I can find a way to free him, too. To let him find peace at last.<br>Only one other being has attempted this ascension to godhood before; the Raven Queen herself. She was previously the <a data-href="Chrysalis Queen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Chrysalis Queen" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chrysalis Queen</a> of <a data-href="Winter" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/winter/winter.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Winter</a> before she ruled the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Shadowfel" data-href="Shadowfel" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/shadowfel/shadowfel.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Shadowfell</a>. But the ascension was not perfect; something went wrong in some way and she became… peculiar. Part of that may have been because of the <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Spellplague" data-href="Spellplague" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/spellplague.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spell Plague</a>, which coincided with her preparations. So, either he knows of some coming cataclysm or he’s simply attempting to brute-force it. I can’t decide which is worse.<br>We decided to explore the rest of this place before making any grand decision. There may be hints left behind that we have not yet seen. We paired off—<a data-href="Deidre" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/deidre.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Deidre</a> and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Smoke-in-Mirrors" data-href="Smoke-in-Mirrors" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Smoke-in-Mirrors" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Smoke</a>, Corvaux and <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Luck of the Draw" data-href="Luck of the Draw" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/luck-of-the-draw.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Luck</a>, Aeren and myself. We searched a library and adjoining bedroom, finding little of note. Most of the books contained lists of <a data-href="Autumn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/autumn/autumn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Autumn</a> authority captains and scouts. We did find an intact scroll that contained musical instructions for making prayer beads. A gift for Deidre, perhaps? In the bedroom, we found an emerald green and gold leaf cloak, a bark-brocade vest, and some cufflinks. The cloak is mine, of course—it’s very nearly the same shade as my doublet!<br>We met up again in the central room where Corvaux and Luck explained that they had found an entrance to a basement. If Deidre’s manor is any indication, there may be a font of power down there.<br><a data-href="Alixandria" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/alixandria.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Alixandria</a> decided that she needed to return to the rangers, and so I asked her to spread the word, to warn whoever she came across.<br>You are not the only one who can manipulate the stories here. And I will make sure the Feywild knows what you are; a thief. Nothing more.<br>We delved into the basement, if you can call it that. It was mostly rubble that we had to squeeze through, bumping and bruising ourselves as we went. If the basement of Deidre’s manor was terrible, this one was worse. There were bones embedded into the roots of the tree and many more in the shallow water. Across the shallow pool, I found myself mired in muck as I pushed past an ivy curtain into a massive chamber. But our exploration halted to a stop there—we heard Luck and Deidre in danger, and rushed across the cavern to help them. What have we gotten ourselves into now?]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/mirri-41.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Mirri 41.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 01:38:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Aerendyl 41]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Day 3 of Firecrest, T.A. 515? | Day 13 in the Feywild<br>
With a ( a very much needed ) helping hand from <a data-href="Corvaux" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/corvaux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Corvaux</a> and <a data-href="Mirri" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/mirri.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mirri</a>, I examined <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Malachai" data-href="Malachai" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Malachai" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">my father</a>'s diary for any further information on this promise magic. That … wound up yielding disturbing insights into the nature of soul disappearances across the planes. The idea that someone – guess who … – might be amassing souls to "brute force" their way into godhood is chilling. This isn't about the handful trapped here, however abhorrent that might already be. This concerns dozens, hundreds, likely even thousands.<br>My father's meticulous research, despite the personal toll it took on him, paints a picture of a vast, shadowy conspiracy. He sought to gain <a data-href="the Raven Queen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/the-raven-queen.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Raven Queen</a>'s favour to gain an audience with her to learn what she knew ( or not ) about the ultimate fate of these souls, as even tracing the path of the river Styx itself yielded no results, apparently.<br>The revelation about the Raven Queen's ascension from a fey entity known as the <a data-href="Chrysalis Queen" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Chrysalis Queen" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Chrysalis Queen</a> to a goddess during the <a data-href="Spellplague" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/spellplague.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spellplague</a> provides historical context for the kind of transformation <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Vestan Tlanbourn" data-href="Vestan Tlanbourn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Vestan Tlanbourn" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Vestan</a> might be attempting. While this might once have been an inspiring tale, it instills me with dread now.<br>What cosmic measure of power are we truly up against?<br>A sound question to ask, especially in light of our failure to clean these bloody ( literally and figuratively ) handprints, these anchor points, off the floor.<br>We decided to look around for more clues. <a data-href="Deidre" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/deidre.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Deidre</a> and <a data-href="Smoke-in-Mirrors" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Smoke-in-Mirrors" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Smoke-in-Mirrors</a> came across a particularly interesting chamber, containing a message written in blood about becoming a vessel for the Abyss is particularly unsettling. Could this be Vestan's own words about his bond with <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Thousand-Eyed Deceiver" data-href="Thousand-Eyed Deceiver" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Thousand-Eyed Deceiver" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Zirel</a>? The inactive spell reminiscent of Leomund's Tiny Hut – according to the more arcanely experienced – suggests our efforts to disrupt the ritual may be having some effect. That's at least somewhat heartening.<br>Mirri and I meanwhile uncovered some items in the ransacked library, including a musical scroll for creating a necklace of prayer beads. The recurring themes of various gemstones in the lyrics feel significant. When I've put together my notes on precious crystals and the like, I would like to compare them to what purpose the poems states these materials will play:<br>“Oak for strength;<br>
Coral to guide;<br>
Jade for purification;<br>
Amber for protection;<br>
Onyx to empower;<br>
Aquamarine for my foundation.”<br>Perhaps once Deidre has had a look – as we believed she in particular would appreciate the items we found. <br>We later ventured into the underground chamber beneath the tree root system, which was both awe-inspiring and horrifying. The bioluminescent plants created a mesmerising atmosphere, but the discovery of countless skulls embedded in the tree roots and the bedding of the small lake spoke of immense suffering.<br>Unfortunately, it didn't take much in terms of what I thought was careful exploration for us to be faced with the threat of Will-o'-Wisps – manifestations of anguished souls. Formidable foes as they might be, we've overcome worse odds before. I mean, we ( though I least of all ) took down a dragon! And abyssal chickens!<br>Oh, I do worry about <a data-href="Grout" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/grout.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Grout</a>, left behind with <a data-href="Ralph" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/animal-companions/ralph.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Ralph</a> at the entrance. I have faith in his ability to either protect himself and Ralph and vice-versa, or run when the need calls, I do, but … the <a data-href="Feywild" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Feywild</a> has thrown some immensely unforeseen surprises our way. Once we're back out and Grout is with us again, I'll need to consider some so-far-unentertained options to protect him during our journey ahead.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/aerendyl-41.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Aerendyl 41.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:37:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Mirri 40]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>Flamecrest, 515 of 3A.<br>
Day 13 in the Feywilds<br>It was a long night and an even longer morning.<br>I spoke with <a data-href="Hallow" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/hallow.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hallow</a>. It was strange for both of us, me returning so soon, but I see that I must make more of an effort to do so in the future. She confided in me her fears, her pain and her anger at her imprisonment. It broke my heart to hear her tell me that there may be a day where I go to her and she cannot remember who I am. The very thought of it hurts.<br>
She shared a vision with me, a lake. Peaceful and serene. And in that dream, a memory of a memory, there was a figure walking beneath the perfumed branches. Someone she loved, loves still. She asked me if the world had forgotten her. I realized that, in all these years, who have I trusted besides her? I can count the number on one hand. I feared… I feared violence, rejection, the imaginations of someone who cannot—or will not—understand her. That it does not matter where she resides, what she appears to be. She loves me, more than anyone else perhaps ever has. Fully. Unconditionally. As I love her.<br>I want to free her. And only he would know who she had been before he bound us together.<br>I woke to another difficult conversation and more guilt than I could stomach. <a data-href="Corvaux" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/corvaux.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Corvaux</a> and I spoke for a time, trading (verbal) blows. I have to give it to them… they know how to exploit a weakness. But they also revealed a weakness of their own; he might be able to sway them far easier than they’d have liked. Another time, I might have laughed. And yet, once… I would have done anything if he’d asked. If he’d taken the time to spin me the same fairytale he’s spun before.<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Aerendyl" data-href="Aerendyl" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/player-characters/aerendyl.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Aeren</a> wanted to—I can’t even write it. I can’t look at him now, not after… 54 years I have gone this alone, and yet the moment a foolish boy with a sweet disposition is placed in my care, I lose what sanity I had left. He’d… I can’t do it again. I can’t survive it a second time. I promised. I promised I would get you home to your mother, to your father, if it was the last fucking thing I do. I can’t fail again. I won’t. I refuse.<br>Corvaux was concerned that I might not be able to do it. To kill him. There was a time, long ago, where I might have doubted it myself. Back when I believed him to be nothing more than an avaricious thief.<br>Thief. He’s a thief. Whatever else he is, whatever else he has become, he is and always has been a thief.<br>
What if this grand plan was never his by design? He only arrived in <a data-href="Irieabor" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Irieabor" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Irieabor</a> just over 100 years ago, as far as I know, at least. That was when he first appeared in the capital, at that party. He did what was necessary to gain access to <a data-href="Hastaerien" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Hastaerien" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Hastaerien</a>’s library, to the books and artifacts of a man connected deeply to the <a data-href="Spring" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/spring/spring.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Spring</a> Court. The <a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Fallen Halls of Eristalon" data-href="Fallen Halls of Eristalon" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Fallen Halls of Eristalon" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Fallen Halls</a> were once the centre of <a data-href="Eristalon" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Eristalon" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Eristalon</a>’s power—what if the Archfey was the mastermind?<br>I spoke with Aeren after he returned from communing with <a data-href="Toraash" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Toraash" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Toraash</a> and I apologized for… earlier. He does remind me of <a data-href="Paelias" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/Paelias" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">Paelias</a> in so many ways, but that is not an excuse. Everything reminds me of Paelias… that is the nature of grief, I suppose. You cannot outrun it; it does not leave you.<br>
When we were all gathered again, I told my friends about my theory and we discussed his purpose here once more. Aeren recalled special properties of the <a data-href="Autumn" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/autumn/autumn.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Autumn</a> court, of its importance in stories. If there was ever a place to change the tale to fit your agenda, it would be here.<br>There was also talk of <a data-href="the Librarian" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/the Librarian" class="internal-link is-unresolved" target="_self" rel="noopener">the Librarian</a>, this "rebel" archfey, risen from the common folk of the <a data-href="Feywild" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations/feywild/feywild.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Feywild</a>, who defies the powers-that-be, delivering information, books, and scrolls to those in need. I’ve heard of her myself—a few friends in the Guild used to invoke her when their heists just weren’t turning out right. And she seemingly always delivered; a letter dropped in the right place, a note in an old book…<br>Or… a contraband book, found in the bag of a drunken student in that tavern, a book written by…<br>Oh, fuck me.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/character-logs/mirri-40.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Character Logs/Mirri 40.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 20:16:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Session Logs]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br><br> <br><br> <br><br> <br><br> <br><br> <br><br><br> <br><br> <br>Navigation
<a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Index" data-href="Index" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/index.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Return to Homepage</a>
<a data-href="Session Logs" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/session-logs.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Session Logs</a>
<a data-href="NPC Directory" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/npc-directory.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">NPC Directory</a>
<a data-href="Lore" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/lore.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Lore</a>
Where in the Worlds
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Locations by Name.md" data-href="Locations by Name.md" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations-by-name.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Locations by Name</a><br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="Locations by Plane.md" data-href="Locations by Plane.md" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/locations-by-plane.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Locations by Plane</a> ]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/session-logs.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Session Logs.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2024 16:59:31 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/summoned_demon.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><content:encoded>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/images/creatures/summoned_demon.png"&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Spellplague]]></title><description><![CDATA[<br>The Spellplague took place 515 years ago, and is considered to be the start of the current age. When Bane, a mortal who had known <a data-href="Mystra" href="https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/entities/npcs/titans/pantheon/mystra.html" class="internal-link" target="_self" rel="noopener">Mystra</a> from before she ascended to godhood, killed her out of jealousy and spite, the Weave was demolished along with her.<br>
The Weave, Mystra's gift to mortals, is a tool used to interact with and harness the raw power of the universe. Mortals with strong connections to the Weave were likewise wiped out.<br>
In the magical vacuum that followed, planes collided and rifts were formed. Despite the devastation, new life was formed as well, including the myconids and kenku, who did not exist prior to the Spellplague.]]></description><link>https://deep-roots-campaign.github.io/terms-and-phrases/spellplague.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Terms and phrases/Spellplague.md</guid><pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 20:11:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>